Lines may divide us, but hope will unite us.
The Boy in the Striped Pyjamas is a drama, war,
history film directed by Mark Herman.
When his family moves from their home in Berlin to a strange new house in Poland, young Bruno befriends Shmuel, a
boy who lives on the other side of the fence where everyone seems to be wearing striped pajamas.
Unaware of Shmuel's fate as a Jewish prisoner or the role his own Nazi father plays in his
imprisonment, Bruno embarks on a dangerous journey inside the camp's walls.
Bruno, played by Asa Butterfield.
Mother, played by Vera Farmiga.
Father, played by David Thewlis.
Shmuel, played by Jack Scanlon.
Gretel, played by Amber Beattie.
Lieutenant Kotler, played by Rupert Friend.
The Boy in the Striped Pyjamas (released as The Boy in the Striped Pajamas in North America)
is a 2008 Holocaust historical drama film written and directed by Mark Herman.
It is based on the 2006 novel of the same name by John Boyne.
Set in Nazi-occupied Poland, the film follows the son of a Schutzstaffel
(SS) officer who befriends a Jewish prisoner of his age.
It was released in the United Kingdom on 12 September 2008.
It received generally positive reviews from critics for its emotional weight, mature themes and
acting but was panned by scholars for misrepresenting elements of the Holocaust.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, nazi,
nationalism, concentration camp, world war ii.
The tone is emotional.